Shawn Liu

■ shawn.yx.liu@gmail.com | □ 408-839-7241 | □ linkedin.com/in/shawn-yx-liu | ⊕ shawnliu.dev

ABOUT ME

Motivated and collaborative fullstack developer with 2 years of professional experience in building enterprise web applications. Proficient in React, Angular, TypeScript, C#.NET, and MS SQL. Demonstrated code ownership and ensured code quality by building automated testing software for internal use. Constantly updating personal and professional development skills with online courses and personal projects.

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Physics

Aug. 2017 - Dec 2021

Professional Experience

Omnicell, Inc.

Dec 2021 – Present

Software Engineer I

Palo Alto, CA

- Built an interactive web app using Angular that supports large-scale distribution of pharmaceutical drugs in health networks, generating over \$44 million in total booking revenue
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs for a robust backend service using ASP.NET, facilitating seamless communication between services for a high-traffic web application managing 2 million active users
- Collaborated with hardware and UI/UX teams to create user-friendly guided interfaces on cloud platform using Angular and Tailwind, reducing prescription process time by 25% and nursing errors by 75%
- Created internal-facing web app with React to automatically generate and scan 150,000 item barcodes for QA testing, expediting system hardening and reducing regression test work every quarter

Omnicell, Inc.

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Software Test Engineer Intern

Cranberry Township, PA

- Engineered a standalone desktop app with Electron and C# that enables developers and QA engineers to test hardware communication while working remotely
- Developed automated UI tests with Ranorex that verify the app's integration with existing inventory management software, ensuring alignment with test-driven development practices
- Wrote Jasmine and Cypress tests for web application's integration with hospital servers, enabling timely bug fixes and bringing automated test code coverage up to 80%

Hitachi Energy

May 2020 – Aug 2020

Software Process Engineer Intern

San Jose, CA

- Identified resource bottlenecks in software development process using a value-based model and presented optimizations to facilitate the company's merge with Hitachi
- Created a mapping and documented workflow for the transition to a customer-oriented Agile development process
- Researched the usage of rule-based software systems in automating decision-making and business logic

PROJECTS

Brain Blitz

Dec 2023 – Present

- Developed a web-based trivia game using React that fetches data from the Open Trivia Database API
- Implemented a websocket server to establish seamless connections for real-time multiplayer gameplay
- Bundled project with Webpack and deployed app online with Netlify and Heroku

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C#, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL

Frameworks: React, Angular, Tailwind, ASP.NET, Socket.io, Cypress, Jasmine

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Swagger, VS Code, Visual Studio, Netlify, Heroku, Jira